Portfolio Github StackOverflow Writings

SUMMARY

Software artisan and author with media and e-governance experience.

SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript/TypeScript, CSS, Python, SQL, GraphQL, Processing, Shell Datastores: Postgre(SQL), MongoDB, Firebase, Redis, DynamoDB, IndexedDB

Operations: *nix/osx, Docker, AWS, GCP, DigitalOcean, Azure, Cloudflare

Frameworks: React, Svelte, Express, FastAPI, NextJS

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer (evenzero.in) Independent Contractor, Remote/India Jun 2018 - Present

Full Stack Web Development Services

- Shipping with self-effacing transparency and care commercial, open-source, and bespoke web products to global business teams and Y-Combinator alumni
- Clientele:
 - Cybrilla, Bengaluru Modernised fintech API, email-service, design library
 - Able, Hyderabad Bespoke front-end project with a premier agency
 - Tattle, New Delhi Open-source WhatsApp Scraper with CMS
 - Salesbeat, UK AWS project for sales automation SaaS product
 - Singularium, Bengaluru Product front-end for an Azure cognitive service
 - Bombay Shirt Company, Mumbai front-end optimisation on factory-tocustomer e-retail solution
 - Autoproctor/Socratease, Bengaluru YC2021 New features, landing page
 - Sense Infinity, Bengaluru Restaurant loyalty management portal
- Specialties: In-app content strategy, Front-end tuning and upgrade, Domainspecific solutions, Customised tooling (Babel, Webpack, Vite)

Correspondent (Equity) NSE Cogencis, Mumbai

Nov 2016 – Jun 2018

Content Strategy, Python, Excel

- Reporting business news in a real-time environment, interviewing CXOs-to-analysts of Technology, Media, Telecom sectors
- Monitoring and interpreting companies' financial results and earnings cycles (including previews and reviews), macro-developments, themes, and sector-wide trends, AGMs, EGMs, briefings and junkets
- Automating routine copies for the wire using existing data
- Cultivating relationships with investors, industry contacts, investor relations personnel, and senior management

Professional Ghostwriter Self-Employed, Chandigarh

Jan 2015 - Sep 2016

Content Strategy

• Turning intellectual property into books, websites, content for global clientele on Upwork and Elance

Account Manager (Trainee)
Goldentouch Consulting Ltd, Tel Aviv

Feb 2015 – Feb 2016

UI/UX, Kindle publishing, Udemy

- Project Management/UI Design of a new Learning app
- Liaised with a development agency on a mobile application prototype
- Co-authored a book based on a top-selling Udemy course

Content Strategist / Bid Manager Redlizard Studioz, Chandigarh Oct 2014 – Feb 2015

macOS, Python

- Designing content strategy (white papers, corporate communications) for Video Games, E-commerce apps and web-apps
- Working with developers for editorial directions to in-game/in-app copy/UI/UX

Upper Division Clerk

Sep 2012 – Mar 2014

Employees' State Insurance Corporation, Ludhiana

Linux, Excel

- Calculating and disbursing physical disability pensions to victims of industrial accidents
- Working with doctors at ESIC hospitals in assessing physical disability arising out of industrial accident

EDUCATION

Bachelor Of Computer Applications Punjab Technical University, Jalandhar 2003 - 2006

CERTIFICATIONS

- Microsoft AZ-104: Microsoft Azure Administrator
- Microsoft Certified Trainer

PUBLICATIONS

- The key to study skills: Simple Strategies to Double Your Reading, Memory, and Focus (Amazon)
- ZenTube : An open-source cross-browser plugin to censor YouTube

HOBBIES

- Reading and writing. Poetry, philosophy, fiction, aphorisms.
- Solo travel.

REFERENCES

References are available on request